But again,
from the lobby here in just a moment.
So good morning, everybody.
We're letting everybody I'm in from the
lobby.
So we'll give it just a moment or two for
everybody to join in.
My name is Dominic Zurlo and I'm the
Center Director for Medical Cannabis and
Psilocybin.
This is the Research and Continuous
Improvement committee from the Medical
Psilocybin Advisory Board and Dan
Jennings is the chair for this committee.
And so just as a reminder to everyone,
because we've gotten the question again a
few times,
the reason why we have all of the cameras
off except for some of the presenters and
some of the staff at Department of Health
is for two reasons.
One,
because we want to ensure there's enough
bandwidth for people who are in more
rural areas or other areas where Internet
may not be as strong.
We want to ensure they have enough
bandwidth to stay in the meeting at least
for as long as possible.
And the second reason is,
and this hits not just from a visual but
also from a spoken word aspect of it,
is Please remember to make sure that what
you say is appropriate for recordings
because we do record these and post them
up on the website so they are available
for the public.
So please make sure that you're using
appropriate language.
And that's the other reason why we have
cameras off because sometimes unbeknownst
to people,
there are things in the background that
we otherwise have to blur and,
and bleep out.
And so we prefer not taking the time on
that and focus on the work itself.
In any case,
thank you everybody for joining with all
of that and the reminders,
I will turn this on over to Dan.
Dan, this is your meeting.
Thank Dominic.
Appreciate that very much.
And I'm real happy to have everybody here
today.
Thank you all very much for coming to the
research and continuous improvement
subcommittee.
Appreciate your being here today.
We'll be going from 9 till 11.
And I just popped the agenda up a little
bit earlier.
But during this first part of our agenda,
we always do our announcements and
introductions.
And I would love to have everybody kind
of introduce themselves.
A couple of things that we would love to
do is do that with your hand raised there.
We'll get to call on you.
And in the meantime,
while you're getting to that point,
I know that we've got a few of our board
members on today.
So definitely wanted to call them out.
I see that Ian is here and I believe that
Brenda's here as well.
So while everybody's getting their hand
raised to do introductions,
I would love for the DoH team if I'll
turn it back over to Dominic real quick
to see if there's anybody that he'd like
to call out on the DoH team introduce and
if there's any announcements also there.
Yeah, thank you, Dan.
Good morning again, everyone.
And so today from our Department of
Health team,
we have assisting us is Johnny Moshe,
who's going to help with the muting and
unmuting for people as they speak.
We have our psilocybin program manager,
Jorge Gonzalez is joining us.
We have our compliance officer,
Leslie Peterson,
our environmental scientist,
Cyrus Rautman.
We have our Medical Director,
Rob Truchner.
We have one of our health educators,
Adrian Estrada, who is also present.
And then we have a few other staff
members who help us with regard to other
areas,
including from administrative and
financial.
We also have our Finance Coordinator and
Director, Selena Montoya,
who is joined in.
And I think that's everybody that we have
from duh.
If I miss somebody, my apologies,
but otherwise, I'll turn it back on.
Over to you, Dan.
Awesome.
Thank you all very much.
So remember for your introductions,
just let us know your name, your location,
where you're coming in from,
any affiliations that you might have.
This is your first time or if you're
returning,
remember just raise your hands and
whenever you're called on,
you'll be unmuted and then you can open
your microphone up and speak.
All right,
and just as a reminder that to raise your
hand in teams on the top banner,
there's a icon with a hand that says
raised and it also if you'd like to
introduce yourself in the chat,
you can do that as well.
Looks like first we've got Don Moser and
Don, I have enabled your mic.
You can unmute when you're ready.
Good morning, my name is Don Moser.
I live in Las Vegas, NM.
I'm not affiliated with anyone.
I'm just a very interested party and I
enjoy learning about this new program.
Thank you so much.
Awesome.
Thank you, Don.
And next we've got Brenda Burgard and
Brenda, you can unmute when you're ready.
Good morning, everyone, and welcome,
newcomers.
I'm Brenda Burgard,
and I chair the education and training
for the Advisory Board here for the
medical psilocybin.
So welcome, everyone.
Thank you.
All right.
And next we've got Kate Hawk.
And Kate, you can unmute him already.
Good morning, everyone.
Kate Hawk.
I live in Santa Fe.
I've got a background in trauma therapy,
psychedelic therapy, therapist training,
harm reduction,
Native American communities and
particularly interested in end of life
care.
Awesome.
Thank you, Kate.
And next we've got Sky Rivers and Sky.
You can unmute when you're ready.
Can you hear me?
Did I do it right?
This is Sky Rivers.
I am with the Santa Fe reporter.
I am covering ongoing news coverage on
this topic.
Very grateful to be here.
I'm also a retired intuitive counselor.
Thank you very much.
So thank you, Sky.
And next we've got Denali Wilson.
And Denali, I've enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Good morning, everyone.
My name is Denali Wilson.
I'm the director of strategic support for
the Healing Advocacy Fund,
which is a nonprofit that supports state
regulated access to psychedelic healing.
And I have not been at this committee for
a while.
So grateful for the opportunity to
reintegrate.
Awesome.
Thanks to Nolly.
And next we've got Doctor Lita.
I think.
Fatemi.
Look, it's showing up as Fatem O today,
but I'm.
I'm pretty sure that you're still the
same person.
You're right.
I mistyped and then it took it and I was
like, oh, I can't edit it.
Thank you for noticing the typo.
Yeah.
I'm Doctor Lita Fatemi.
I'm an academic physician,
founder of the Conscious Physician
Psychedelics Academy, and I'm,
I'm also a Hospice physician with ABQ
Hospice and palliative.
And I love what I do and I love being
here with you all and have a it's
wonderful.
Thank you for doing what you do.
So thank you.
And next we've got Ian Dunn.
Good morning everyone.
My name is Ian Dunn.
I'm the therapy medical Advisory Board.
I'm just happy that everyone could make
it today and happy to participate in any
way I can.
Awesome.
Thanks, Ian.
And next we've got Danielle Leonard and I
have enabled your mic and you can unmute.
Hi, I'm Danielle Leonard,
I live in Santa Fe.
I research with New Mexico Highlands
University and I'm a therapist focusing
mainly in acceptance and commitment
therapy.
Awesome.
Thanks, Danielle.
And next we've got Catherine Warnock.
And Catherine, I've enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Good morning, everybody.
My name is Catherine Warnock.
I am located in Las Cruces.
I am a psychedelic therapist.
I've been doing this work for years and
I'm just excited to be a part of this.
I've really struggled to attend this
particular meeting just because I've had
a lot of conflicts, but I finally am here,
so I'm excited to be a part of it.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks Catherine.
And next we've got Gregory Evans.
And Gregory, I have enabled your mic.
Good morning.
My name is Gregory Evans.
I am an independent researcher in home
oncologist based out of Santa Fe, NM Yep,
that's about it.
Good morning.
And next, we've got Shin.
Sonia and I have enabled your mic.
Oh, good morning, everyone.
My name is Sonia Shin.
I'm with the Office of Alcohol Misuse
Prevention at New Mexico Department of
Health.
I'm a physician.
I see patients in Gallup,
and it's my first time attending the
committee.
So excited to be here.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks, Sonia.
And next we've got Teresa Bertonson and I
have enabled your mic.
You can unmute when ready.
And just reminder for unmute,
there is a icon at the top banner that
says mic that you'll have to click on
there to unmute.
Sometimes if no mic is selected,
there's a drop down next to it as well
that you might be able to select a mic
that will work.
And if not,
maybe just try dropping something in the
chat.
And if all else fails,
dropping off the meeting and then
rejoining will sometimes fix those issues
as well.
All right,
so looks like Theresa might still be
having some issues.
So next we will go to Jay Webster and Jay,
I have enabled your mic.
You can unmute when ready.
Sorry.
Hi, my name is Jarvis Webster.
I'm a New Mexico resident.
I live in Hidalgo County.
I grow gourmet mushrooms and I want to
see if I can help with this program.
Awesome.
Thank you.
All right.
And I think that was all the hands that
that we had up.
And we've got some introductions in the
chat as well.
I'll let's see,
we can go ahead and read those as well.
We have Nifa Naya Washington with us from
Santa Fe Co,
director of psychedelic mental health
Access Alliance.
We have Carolyn Kroland from Whoa,
let's see from Atlanta, GA.
This is our second meeting and is
affiliated with Fireside Project.
We have Eileen Brewer.
Let's see.
Oh, she is sick.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Eileen,
community organizer and psychedelic
educator for more than 10 years work with
Cluster Busters and have worked with the
Psychedelic and Pain Association in
helping with patient and community
education.
On this committee, we got Shane McDaniel,
integration coach and hopefully future
cultivator Clovis and Logan and Jessica
Eden, LCSW,
psychedelic assisted therapist in
practice in New Mexico and Colorado.
This is her first meeting.
Welcome.
All right, and back to you, Dan.
Thank you all.
Everybody appreciate it and it's great to
see a lot of returning.
And for those of you that are coming for
your first time here,
really appreciate you being here.
This is actually a really good audience.
So thank you all for coming out to this
meeting today.
Got some.
I think really exciting things that's
been going on with this group.
Our intersessional work groups have been
doing amazing things and I really
appreciate their time.
James Brown, Gregory Evans,
Danielle Leonard and everybody that has
been helping to come together with some
of the recommendations for this committee
have been fantastic.
And so one of the things that we'll be
looking at here for our next wave here is
just to hear kind of report work,
group report outs.
And then we do want to do some in this
meeting,
a little bit of clarification of what
other committees are working on and doing.
And so that that way we know our role as
it is for support for those other
committees.
So I've done a little bit of break out of
some of the things that our committee is
tasked with,
what other committees are working on
because they're doing the actual work and
what our committee is kind of responsible
for to be that support for those
activities too.
So hopefully that will kind of clarify a
little bit.
And it's great to see Ian and Brenda here
on the call too.
So I'm hopeful that they'll be able to
kind of chime in as well on some of the
things they're working on in their
committees.
Because with a lot of y'all that are here,
I know that your your,
your heart and passion fits in with a lot
of those committees.
And here in your introductions really
means that I want to make sure that cross
work happens there.
That way we'll be able to clarify if it
stays in the RACI committee.
And then I do want to,
I've kind of done a little bit of work on
what we can do in RACI committee to break
up this work and hopefully for our next
Sprint priorities and kind of line out
over the next set of months kind of what
that might look like.
So I've done a little bit of splitting
things out.
I'm hopeful it might help and we'll just
kind of see where it goes.
Love to hear your feedback.
Always raise your hand if there's
anything we'll be able to call on you or
drop it.
Of course, in the chat,
I can see the chat going too.
So if you do put something over there,
make sure that you just put it in there
so we can see that.
So our first kind of Sprint is going to
be our interceptional report work group
report outs.
We did have 3 committees.
We have an outcome or challenging events,
adverse expense monitoring reporting.
We have emergency preparedness and
response recommendations and patient and
community education recommendation.
And so I know that I I saw Danielle on
and Gregory on, I didn't see James on.
But I'll kind of turn it over to one of
you, both of you,
so that you can just kind of like share
out in this time what has been happening
and what y'all have been meeting on and
things that have moved forward,
things that might be stuck,
things that we might need to work on.
So I'll turn that over and Gregory or
Danielle, if you want to raise your hand,
we'll get your mic opened up for you.
Well, let's see.
And I can.
Let's see.
I'll allow your mic.
Do you have anything you were going to
present either or like from your screen?
I do.
I can send it in or I can present,
if that's OK.
No.
Yeah, I'll.
Yeah.
I'll just raise you the presenter.
Yeah.
And I don't know, no yellow buttons,
right?
Exactly.
Don't, don't press the yellow button.
Don't push the yellow button.
James is away.
He had to go pick up his kids from
college on the East Coast.
He mentioned that he was gonna try to
call in,
but he was not sure about service.
So I've agreed to kind of take care of
this part.
Danielle is with us.
Are are you on mic, Danielle?
Hi, yes,
I'm here and I can speak to the reporting
multicultural reporting for the racy
group from our work group.
Awesome.
Give me one second to figure out how to
present slides.
How do I switch this?
Well, I guess swap.
There we go.
Now we can bear with me.
I was hoping to have a few extra minutes.
I just walked in the house.
I don't.
I was.
That's why I always like.
OK.
Are Are you ready?
I'll stall.
So that's OK.
Nope, I'm here.
I just need to get this presented and
actually while, while you're doing that,
I'll go ahead and read 1 introduction.
So, Teresa, I apologize.
I, I, I think I'm going to put your name.
I apologize.
Bear Berton Bertonson I apologize if that
was not the way you pronounced.
I cannot enable my mic.
I'm Teresa Bertonson,
LMFTLPCCI live in Taos and work in Los
Angeles, New Mexico and Hawaii.
I am a trauma therapist consultant for
multiple treatment teams.
I am a EMDRIA approved consultant and
trainer.
I have completed the MAPS and CIS
training and psychedelic assisted therapy
and research.
I'm part of a small team of psychiatrists,
physicians and clinicians who mimic
psychedelic therapy clinical trials for
research presentations such as Thank you
for being here and on over.
OK, is that slide up?
Yes.
Cool.
I want to take a minute to appreciate
Danielle Leonard for being here,
the work that and insight that she's
contributed to our little.
It's not a gang.
It's just like a group of nerds has been
instrumental.
I'm going to burn through the on the top
half of it,
just a quick little introduction,
go through the emergency preparedness
stuff and then hand it off to Danielle as
we go through her stuff.
And if I need to kind of like help
navigate the slides, we'll do that.
We have been working on a number of
things and and we'll kind of expose where
some of those things are and what kind of
help that we need moving forward and what
gaps we could use help unblocking.
James was kind enough to volunteer us for
picking up the emergency data.
And so one of the things that we did was
we looked at it from terms of outcomes
reporting and we went in and found
research defining the existing reporting,
research on what have been termed as
adverse events,
emergencies where emergency medical
institutions have been engaged.
Two major Seminole publications,
Copra ET al 2022 and Simon ET al 2024.
The first one is EMT engagement.
And the major revealing factor for when
you isolate it down to psilocybin or it's
not even psilocybin,
it's just mushroom use,
is that it was mostly young men that were
having challenging experiences.
Like if as you read through the lines,
there's one in 1800 and the the data in
that paper is very revealing.
Simon ET al.
Is a poison set of mushroom exposures
from 2013 to 2022.
It's a 10 year study the.
Major outcomes were 4.
2% compared to 43% for moderate outcomes.
The thing that we saw is after six hours,
most people had fully recovered and by 7
days,
100% of the people had recovered from
their experience.
The number of pediatric exposures was
four O 9.
One of the things that I wanted to point
out in this is that there was no
definition of like how those infant,
how those pediatric cases were introduced
to the mushroom,
whether it was like poor storage or
whether it was toddler eats mushroom in
yard.
There's no disambiguation in that study
to separate those types of things.
Overall,
the substance identity was completely
unconfirmed across all the studies,
dosage was unknown,
and therapeutic context was not
considered.
Breakdown between psychological and
physiological engagement.
It's kind of interesting the
psychological stuff,
all of our well trained facilitators and
practitioners in the industry will find
that those are commonly misunderstood
conditions,
whereas the physiological conditions,
tachycardia, nausea and vomiting,
high blood pressure and seizures with
passing out being like the highest
percentage on that.
It's interesting to kind of read that
data and see what it is that the caveat
on seizures is those cases were all
connected to Trazodone Co medication as
far as sensitive mouse today.
And please let me know when I start to
run out of time because we've got yeah,
let me know when I hit 5 minutes.
Medical interventions generally involve
IV fluids, benzos, antiemetics,
and very rarely intubation.
There's very little like specific data
about where those ventilation and
intubation instances occurred.
It's almost,
it's probably worth investigating,
but low priority as we continue to look
through the data.
The main thing that our group has been
focused on is trying to figure out a way
that when we approach reporting outcomes
on what are considered out adverse
experiences,
we're able to filter out challenging
experiences from adverse events.
The primary instruments to that we're
utilizing to follow challenging
experiences is CEQ 26 and it has a number
of paired instruments that augment it.
And then for adverse events,
our primary goal is to find a way to
either a adopt APATAE into our reporting
structure or to modify the pro CTCAE.
If we do,
and we'll talk about this a little bit
later, if we do adopt the PO,
the pro CTACTCAE as a modified structure,
we're basically just gonna fold the PATAE
in into that.
Essentially,
what's not built is the screening
protocols, collection workflows,
and the reporting forms that
operationalize all of the above.
The targets and instruments are defined,
but the implementation is essentially the
deliverable that we're hoping to get to
by the 11th hour.
On to multicultural competency.
Danielle, I have laid out some slides.
If for any reason you need me to jump
around, please just let me know.
And if you want me to talk and jump in,
I can handle that as well.
OK, cool.
I actually have some slides as well.
Oh, take over, please,
because I am still editing these.
Let me jump out.
I love that.
Thank you so much.
All right, I'm gonna elevate you,
Danielle.
So yeah, like we were saying,
just don't press the yellow button that
says end meeting.
But other than that, let's see.
Oh, I see, I see.
Cool.
Do you have a little icon that says share
next to that?
Yeah,
I'm pressing share and browse my computer.
No.
How do I go on online with it?
So there should be like a thing it in the
share if you've got a window open in your
browser that has what you wanna show that
should be available in the window section
where it's it should say window and like
maybe like a number in parentheses and
what whichever window that you're looking
for should be in there.
Fabulous.
All right, sweet.
We can see multicultural competency in
psilocybin services.
Yeah, So let me go to the next.
Gregory already covered us.
This is the presentation on our cultural
research findings.
I just wanted to explain that we're the
racy committee.
So we're doing reporting,
but we ended up having to cover
everything across the whole program
because what we're reporting on has to be
embedded in the program.
So we have.
We know what we're measuring.
So fortunately,
with professional training,
we don't have to reinvent the wheel.
Training in multicultural care has grown
across behavioural health professions
over several decades,
especially in graduate programs.
Since 2002,
the APA Ethics Code with Standards 201
A&
B on boundaries of competence requires
practitioners to work only within areas
of demonstrated competence,
and that includes cultural competence
also.
The APA multicultural Guidelines that
were adopted in 2017 extend this across
all domains of practice,
research and education.
So these these can be adopted directly
into our program certification.
And here I'd like to say I'm sorry I
haven't managed to get to the training
and education committees and I hope to be
enlightened very, very shortly.
So Graduate Training for Therapists and
counsellors shares a framework organised
around awareness, knowledge,
skills and action.
There's also a text that's used
extensively in graduate programs called
Counselling the Cultural Diverse by Sue
ET al for accredited counselling and
psychology programs,
and it covers awareness of all of our own
individual values,
biases and worldview knowledge.
Having knowledge of diverse client
backgrounds and worldviews,
skills in culturally responsive
intervention and communication,
and more recently they added action to
encourage people to actively work toward
equity and inclusion.
So my point with all this is that the
field has already established clear
baseline over for for multicultural
competency training.
And this can be used by our program and
for people, you know,
particularly for people who haven't had
formal training for everyone, really.
Typically multicultural competency covers
race and ethnicity, gender,
socio economic status, sexual orientation,
gender identity, religion, spirituality,
disability, immigration,
language and intersectionality.
And there's a list of what's generally
covered in training,
the cultural humility, bias awareness,
religion and spiritual diversity,
the intersectional everything I just
covered basically.
And of course,
psychedelic psychotherapy adds another
dimension that requires additional
awareness and training because material
surfaces at the height and depth and
speed, as we all well know,
and it includes strong emotions, trauma,
and these other heightened sensitivity.
So the stakes around cultural imposition
are higher than in standard therapy
sessions.
So in this context,
multicultural common C isn't just about
respectful communication.
It includes a sensitivity to world view,
spirituality, language, music, symbolism,
participant autonomy and agency.
So Gregory mentioned Pulitzki ET al,
ET al.
He's got a couple of papers I refer to
here.
He's got a comprehensive framework work
for adverse events in psychedelic
psychotherapy that I think we, we,
our group thinks will be very helpful for
this program.
He notes the importance of spiritual,
existential,
religious and theological dimensions in
psychedelic care,
and he has identified a very wide range
of adverse events with direct
multicultural relevance.
I'm not going to read them all off,
but a couple that really interested in me
was spiritual one.
The spiritual and religious injury,
which includes the resurfacing of prior
religious abuse and Politsky flags.
This and the therapist facilitate A
tendency to reframe all difficult
experiences as growth in the in in,
particularly in psychedelics.
But he's clear that this can result in
genuine harm going unacknowledged and
unaddressed with regard to spiritual or
religious injury.
He also talks about culturally neutral
therapeutic frames that aren't actually
neutral.
One that's really interesting is the idea
that therapies present themselves as
culturally neutral when they're not
always.
Like CBT is shown to have a poor cultural
fit with some Native American populations
because of its assumptions around the
self rationality.
You know,
don't believe everything that you think
and it doesn't always align with other
cultural values.
So in considering all this,
our recommendations for collecting data
follow from that.
So first of all,
multicultural competency should be a
certification requirement for everyone
involved.
Second,
participant preferences need to be
assessed during preparation.
Politsky one of the things he says a lot
is we ask rather than assume.
That would encompass framing, music,
cultural concerns and prior harmful
materials.
Third, we need in session protocols.
Belle ET al.
Says that training matters,
but that many psychedelic manuals and
practice guidelines still under address
culturally responsive behaviour during
the session itself.
4th Therapeutic con Congruence.
This is something Gregory's really worked
on a lot,
so it's making a good fit between the
client's preferences and the care model.
Gregory talks about matching clients to
practitioners where possible,
not just matching A modality or
therapeutic approach or framework.
A client might feel safe with someone who
shares their cultural background or who
has general cultural knowledge or speaks
their first language.
Of course,
perfect match is not always available,
but it can be a goal.
And lastly,
the the cultural framework connects
directly back to the research program.
We need brief practical data collection
at every stage of the process.
So this is our proposed reporting pathway.
It follows the treatment process we've
been talking about.
So a therapist preparation report would
capture what was learned about the client
before the session,
what are their preferences, risks,
sensitivities, what's their readiness.
A facilitator session during during the
session would capture what's actually
happening in the room,
what approach was used,
what cultural or spiritual material arose,
Were there any distress or or boundary
issues?
And then therapist integration notes
would look would ask how did the client's
cultural and spiritual framework shape
their meaning making and were there any
concerns.
And then a participant post a client post
integration feedback would capture did
they feel respected,
did the care match what they asked for,
and were there any harms.
So this data can all evaluate whether
multicultural competency is actually
being delivered and it can be brief
enough not to create a lot of burden and
still capture what matters.
So we had a little meeting before here
and Desba came to it, which was fantastic.
And she gave us some excellent feedback.
And I thought it'd just be good to share
some of her comments and,
and a bit of a response.
She noted that the language of research
is very academic and it is.
And I know that that can be, you know,
exclusionary for for different
stakeholders.
And research does tend toward academic
language.
And this is the racy committee.
So it's not surprising.
But these concepts can all be expressed
in ways that feel more culturally
grounded for the communities we're
serving.
And it'd be great if other people wanted
to take it in that direction.
She also talked about the spiritual
landscape and the wide diversity of
cultural and spiritual traditions here in
in New Mexico.
The dominant frameworks in psychedelic
culture might not always reflect them.
There's quite a list there that goes
beyond, you know, the,
the commonly talked about white Hispanic
native breakdown here.
And then she also spoke about the
complexities of cultural identity.
She knows, she,
she mentioned that participants often
carry multiple cultural influences and
that sometimes they're only partially
connected to their traditions,
which could could be emotionally
challenging for them or they might not
have a settled spiritual or cultural
identity.
So this this comes back to the importance
of the therapeutic relationship and
cultural sensitivity of the therapist and,
and the program framework.
So this,
all of this brings up a lot of different
questions.
There's I've, I've mentioned 3 here.
Importantly,
how does this work that the racing
committee doing connect with what the
cultural and training and education
committees have already developed?
We don't want to duplicate work or build
in a in a different direction.
And as I said, I haven't,
I haven't had the opportunity to meet
with them.
And then the question of cultural
exchange versus extractive practice.
So many,
I know many facilitators draw on an
indigenous shamanic traditions and have
trained with indigenous teachers.
But is lineage training sufficient or are
there broader obligations around
attribution,
benefit sharing and and community consent?
Salad One and his colleagues have done
important work on this with eight ethical
principles that include benefit sharing,
community consent and and reparation.
And then lastly, who's I?
I can talk more about this if anyone's
interested or I think I've got the paper
at the end in the bibliography.
But lastly, who's missing from the room?
The literature is consistent that
psychedelic research has been shaped by a
narrow demographic.
And as we build the program,
I think this is a question worth sitting
with.
So this is a brief look at the core
issues involved in multicultural
competency and psilocybin services.
We have the professional and ethical
baseline,
the particular considerations of
psychedelic therapy,
what the adverse research event research
tells us,
and some starting recommendations for
reporting and data collection.
I just want to say each of these areas
has an extensive research base.
The Politsky adverse events framework
could occupy a full session.
The Indigenous Knowledge and cultural
exchange question has a rich and actually
quite contested body of scholarship,
but we've kept this deliberately wide,
ankle wide angle so that we can keep it
open for discussion,
and I'm happy to share this paper with
anyone who wants it.
But one very last final thought.
New Mexico Department of Health has a
real opportunity here because much of the
existing psychedelic research has been
shaped by white university student
samples,
and even though more recent clinical
trials have included older participants,
the samples do remain predominantly white,
which is a well documented limitation in
the literature,
and it significantly constrains how
generalizable the findings are.
So with this psilocybin program built
with multicultural competency at its core,
that can serve a genuinely diverse and
underserved population.
It can produce research that reflects
this genuine diversity,
and it'll be a meaningful contribution to
the literature and it won't have already
existed in the field.
And that's going to open up funding
opportunities because multicultural and
HealthEquity research continues to be
important priorities for federal and
grant funding.
Although I think the federal policy
landscapes changing,
but opportunities can flow through the
state through places like SAMSA affiliate
researchers,
through NIMH and Nida and through private
foundations like HAFTA and EUSONA or
through state appropriations.
And that means the multicultural piece is
not a cost to this program,
it's a long term asset.
So thank you.
Thank you very much,
Danielle and Gregory both of y'all for
really routing everything that you
brought back to the committee and
research and this was fantastic.
I really appreciate it.
We've got about.
Do you mind,
do you mind if I end cap that really
quick?
I know we're short on time.
Well, no, it's fine.
We got 8 minutes for the comments for
everybody.
But yes, please go right ahead.
Yeah, I'll take 30 to 45 seconds.
Basically the outstanding like the the
comment,
some of the major comments that we need
from the committee is 3 tis to approach
one of three potential pathways.
Either we want to adopt APATAE or we want
to authorize pro CTCAE at with the
adaption clause allowed in that
instrument or we want to make a concerted
effort towards reaching out to Emery and
Politzky to really answer those questions
about what their what their position on
our adoption of that is.
I also wanted to make note that the
circle of care organization has been do
has been implementing a lot of these
culturally informed and identity
enriching and embracing parameters in
their model.
And I know that they're already connected
into the framework of this program,
but I just wanted to honor like the work
that they've done before any of us even
thought about coming into the room.
But yeah, thank you.
Oh, Dan, you're muted.
Yeah, perfect.
Thanks.
Yeah, I said something very important.
No, Gregory, thank you very much for that.
I think that for the end of today's
session,
let's go ahead and make sure that we get
a lead on your question about do we move
forward on the PATAE or the pro CTAE.
So that's a perfect thing to hit before
we exit this meeting today.
So thank you.
And we have about 5 minutes before our
next beat,
which is cross committee alignment,
which will be a perfect time for I know
that Brenda's here and Ian is here.
I would love for both of them to be able
to share with this committee some of the
things that y'all have worked on through
your committees and where this kind of
comes together with us.
Some things that might go back to your
committee,
some things that you could leave with us
as well,
but anybody that would like to make a
comment during this time,
please make sure you raise your hand
share.
This will be about what we just heard
from both Gregory and from Danielle.
So please go right ahead.
Brenda's hand up.
Hello, everyone.
Thank you, Daniel,
you did a wonderful job kind of pulling
everything out and,
and taking a really good close look at
this.
And, and what we're looking at here,
because this is exactly what we,
I think mostly we've been struggling with
is the multicultural aspect of bridging
this gap between, you know,
the predominantly white culture and the
medical issue medical program that is
kind of set up here and bringing this in.
This is a really important part of what
we are here in New Mexico.
And I think as we keep this multicultural
part open,
it keeps us also growing in this arena to
include everyone in this and,
and actually giving it more, more,
more space,
more understanding and incorporating some
other things that maybe that we're not
seeing right now.
But this is this is exactly what we we've
been needing in this program because I
think this is where maybe other programs
have just kind of maybe touched on or,
you know, glanced over.
But you know,
thank you for doing all of this work
because you really dove into all the
research that is there right now.
And this is so important because I think
New Mexico is very different in,
in this bringing all of this knowledge
and, and it still continues to grow.
I mean,
we're learning as we're actually looking
at some of this material and reading
about it and trying to formulate
something.
So thank you again for bringing this to
light.
Thanks, Brendan.
I appreciate it.
It's fantastic.
And Ian, perfect.
Yeah.
I just wanted to also say thank you guys
for this presentation.
It was really nice.
I have definitely tried to make us as
culturally competent as possible because
I think we need a generalized return in
medicine to patient preference.
And oftentimes that gets overlooked in
our current medical system.
And they'll just say, well,
this medicine works best or this
situation is what you're supposed to do.
And so often is that not the best
scenario for every patient?
It's not.
We shouldn't be using blanket
recommendations.
So the ability to take time and just
recognize their different starting points
for each person in terms of their
cultural heritage and what they've
experienced,
I think is a very great example.
I also want to reiterate what they were
saying before in that we do a lot of the
research is concentrated in one race
group.
And so we have the opportunity to return
this medicine back to the communities
that it it had thrived in if they want to
participate in the medical system.
And I think that is a really great
opportunity as well.
And then just to provide my insight,
I'm preferential to CTCAE, but I will,
this is my first time at this committee.
So I am definitely not the one that
should be making that decision.
That's OK.
I appreciate.
That's why I wanted you to,
to be here to kind of provide and
actually, and I don't know.
So if this is putting on the spot for
anything you could tell me.
Nope, skip this one.
But is there anything from your
committees that you wanted to share with
this committee that might have come out
from recommendations that your committees
want to move forward that could help us
in alignment with what y'all are working
on?
So right now we have built a framework
for risk stratification for patient.
And so one of the things while we are
going to have to present a Phase 1 based
on the research that we have when it
comes to maintaining this program and
ensuring that we keep up with evidence
based practice.
I think a, a,
a standardized collection such as CTCAE
would allow us to update and keep it
relevant to what people are actually
experiencing when we take into
consideration these other situations.
I have rarely seen in a hospital a
patient without a single comorbidity.
It doesn't happen.
You never have just one thing unless
they're very young.
But so being able to study and say, OK,
is this causing harm to people?
Are we actually benefiting them?
Are we throwing people, you know,
into the deep end,
being able to receive what they're
actually experiencing?
Because another thing that is important
to me to at least consider as we go on
and as we continue to collect research is
when we had medical cannabis,
the potency went through the roof.
So I'm anticipating that the potency for
psilocybin will also try to creep its way
up in one way or another.
And so the ability to say, OK,
this manufacturer or this purse,
this facility is making something that is
consistently causing, you know,
deep paranoia or some severe,
severe nausea, gastrointestinal issues,
something like that to be able to respond.
Yeah.
But that's all I had for right now.
Perfect.
Thank you.
I know that Greg would probably respond
back on that,
but I did want to see Doctor Fatemi's
been waiting for just a second.
So Greg,
if you hold that for just one moment and
Doctor Fatemi.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, please.
Fatemi's actually in our our work group.
Oh, perfect.
Great.
Thank you for the reminder.
Yeah no, thank you so much for this work.
It's so important and I'm from a
different culture and spiritual
background and I love how you guys are
touching on all of that and including
what we need here cuz the research out
there is just a lot,
some applies and some doesn't to our
community.
And I love you know what Ian brought up
the the idea of giving people back their
power and agency.
In fact, in our in in our group,
that's what we are constantly talking
about.
That each individual has agency and that
we need to tell them that here are the
tools,
but I'm not the one walking this path for
you.
No one is what the individual and to give
them options is so important to really
evolve how the medical practice is
implemented as we have it.
So thank you so much for the work I have
to leave to attend to our Academy.
We have a lecture coming on.
But thank you so much for this and have a
lovely day.
Thank you.
OK, Gregory.
I got distracted.
Yeah, I kind of want to put yeah, yeah,
sorry.
I just want to,
I kind of want to push back on the CATAE
if I just to,
to put a put a note in that like and
don't and I don't want to speak for the
entirety of the workgroup.
So I would appreciate Danielle kind of
clarifying some of my statements that
might feel harsh,
but the CATAE is hands down dangerous to
implement because it doesn't allow us to
separate challenging from adverse events.
The CATAE offers a pro version which
would allow us to modify the instrument
to the context of our needs,
but we cannot measure adverse events on a
cancer treatment platform.
We are very uniquely different.
And so I'll post a link to the work and
how it's framed so people can explore
that.
And I'll post that in the chat in just a
minute.
The other thing that I wanted to kind of
point out and maybe get a little bit,
maybe encourage Daniel to talk to talk,
talk about a little bit more if we have
time is the in I,
I made notes like the influence ability.
So like when when a practitioner comes in
with their like subconscious framework
and it doesn't align with somebody as
sensitive as they are.
Like I had a very awesome conversation
with with someone in the community
yesterday who like couldn't handle
administering MDMA because they had a bad
relationship with it.
What they found later is that like,
their patients were having a bad
experience because their psychological
framework had like an unintended
influence on that space.
So the level of awareness that a person
has maybe gates their ability to practice
true sensitivity.
So just in, in, in, in that, in,
back in that alignment space.
You know,
I had another question for somebody,
but yeah, please, Danielle.
Yeah, go ahead.
And Danielle, we got, oh, sorry, sorry,
sorry.
Yeah, No, I hear you, Gregory.
With both those things.
I think that's what the training is about.
That's what the training is intended to
do.
Those first two points, cultural humility,
which encourages ongoing self reflection
and openness to learning from the client.
And then really particularly bias
awareness.
I, I went through these programs myself.
It's that it's,
it's a deep dive into what my personal
and systemic biases that might affect how
I relate to other people,
which is a process that students get put
through and that the certification for
this training program can do.
And it's never going to be perfect.
But you know,
the world's not going to be perfect.
And I think just as important as like
clinical handoff,
like if you have a patient that is
expressing a condition that maybe was
masked or not disclosed,
like cultural handoff is vitally
important as well.
If you find that you're ethically not
suited for a specific treatment like
understanding your network and building
relationships outside to bring in the
appropriate care is something yeah.
Anyways,
we're we're get we're bridging into
guidance.
Exactly.
But that's exactly where what what
Danielle mentioned it's it's a it's the
continuous improvement.
And this is where Brendan training
committee can continue on to look at what
additional professional development and
those kind of things look like.
But we can work together on those kind of
things to report back out to these other
committees.
And I want to read into the comments.
Reuben Sutter and D appreciate the
presentation, agree with Doctor Fatemi,
an honor in importance to honor agency
and autonomy for the individual seems
central to the healing process.
And so thank you for that intersectional
work.
I'm we'll continue this,
I'm going to continue this discussion as
kind of what our next steps are going to
look like here towards the end of today.
But this is a perfect time to kind of
talk about that cross committee alignment
because there's a lot of ways and parts
that we can we work together with those
other committees on.
I really folk,
I really like the idea of how we can work
together.
So I've tried to kind of put together a
little bit of a,
a way that I feel this is again, feel,
but is where I'd like to kind of go from.
Is that what our committee does?
And what other committees that kind of
have a, a, a,
a hand in what our racy responsibilities
are and then bi directional work that we
can do together on this.
So some of the easiest things, of course,
our committee is responsible for like
data and monitoring.
And so there's like 4 big things,
the core data elements,
the outcome monitoring,
valuation frameworks and population level
equity trends.
So the idea that we look at is like there
are certain things that we do.
That's what that second column is.
These are the things that we'll be
working on.
But other committees that have kind of
the lead in a lot of this include that
third column there.
So we want to make sure that as our other
committees are coming up with rules and
content that we're mindful of those
things and make sure that our committee
for the data monitoring are looking at it.
But what we can do,
the BI directional work in the fourth
column then is what we can work together
on.
So I'm not going to because I'm leaving
this up on the screen so that you can
read it or take a snap of it.
And at the end I'll have like a link to
this.
But I just want that to be one thing that
we kind of look at.
Then we also have kind of a safety and
harm reduction component to what our
responsibilities are including adverse
event reporting standards,
the harm reduction practices,
restraining medication interaction and
guidance emergency preparedness.
Now again,
that crosses over dramatically with a lot
of other committees,
meaning we're not making the rules for
those things.
We're talking about what our committee
can do when those rules and contents are
being brought.
So what can we do by directionally?
We don't, for example,
set the screening criteria,
but we talk about what screening related
data that needs to be in there.
And so a lot of what Danielle and Gregory
have already talked about is exactly that.
So we're trying to make sure that we're
respectful of the other committees work,
but what can we do from this committee?
And then one of the last sets, of course,
equity and ethics,
a lot of exactly what Danielle had spoken
about just a minute ago from all the way
from ethical practices,
research practices to form consent,
patient education, where again,
other committees are responsible for that
core content.
But we are able to really be here to kind
of share a lot of the research,
which was exactly what we just saw today,
which was fantastic to say.
Here's the research around that and the
things that we need to be mindful of.
And then the last thing, of course,
feedback and continuous improvement.
And that's really where we stand up the
most.
Is that as the program really is
operational and data and information is
coming back in to the program,
then this committee can really look at
the the the process, the reviews.
What we need to look at is whenever
there's issues for safety and fit and
mismatch and harms and then make sure
that that is bubbled up.
And then if there's changes that need to
be made to the program, what we can do.
So as I just wanted to one of the last
things from our last committee was just
to make sure that from from my mind is
kind of this is where I felt it made
sense for me to line out where kind of
our Venn diagrams overlap a little bit,
but where we kind of stay on on on
courses to what we need to work on.
So that's why I appreciate those of you
that are on other committees and bringing
some of that back to this.
And if you are on those other committees
to take back to those committees,
some of these things too,
I would love if there's comments,
feedback,
thoughts that you have about this part
that I kind of shared.
Please raise your hand and let me know so
we can open your mic on that.
And while you're doing that,
if there's anything you want to add,
I'll read from the comments.
Eileen Brewer Since the last meeting,
I've been focusing on the integration
piece and I've created a section in the
document below.
Beginning on page 2,
I connected with experts in integration
in Mexico to find out what they believe
is most important to share with the
general public, various communities,
and those interested in medical
psilocybin services.
Next,
I intend to focus on education in schools
as that was discussed at the last meeting,
and I will be connecting with
stakeholders who have considered this
carefully.
I also plan to focus on identifying
communities that may need different kinds
of messaging, veterans by pocket, cetera.
And there's a link to the Google doc.
And then Gregory Post said,
here's the core of Politsky ET al and the
PATAE framework.
And Eileen, unfortunately,
I have to log off.
Thanks so much for the great work.
So just wanted to read that into the
comments.
Anybody that wanted to kind of share
anything about, like I said,
our work for the racy committee and the
overlap from other committees.
Cool.
I see Denali's hand up Denali again on
mute.
When you're ready, morning again.
And Dan,
this looks like a really wonderful plan.
Thanks for laying it out for us.
I just wanted to offer and I feel slowly
for not thinking of it sooner,
but I've been working with.
There's a cohort of three faculty between
the School of Social Work and the School
of Public Health at NMSU who are selected
for EU PEP Fellowship,
which is a national fellowship for
integrating psychedelic curriculum.
Not in, I think we,
we talk a lot about in training and
education,
like specifically curriculum for
facilitators,
but this is about integrating it into
schools of social work,
schools of public health,
schools of nursing.
ANYWAYS, it's really great that three,
we have 3 representatives from New Mexico
institution as a part of that cohort.
And so I've been trying to find ways to
integrate them into the work of the
department and the subcommittees.
And I feel silly that I didn't think
about this committee as a really great
opportunity,
especially as you're thinking about.
Yeah, but it just was an enumerated goal,
like bringing this into our state schools.
I think they'll be a great resource.
So unless you have a different suggestion
of how to make that connection,
I'll just plan to send an e-mail
introduction with those three folks,
and then maybe we can set up a meeting.
Or if there's another,
another opportunity that you think Dan is,
is better for that connection,
I'm happy to hear it.
Actually,
I'm going to leave this to our
intercessional work groups because I feel
that I mean that through the medical
psilocybin e-mail address is the perfect
way to do it.
But I think that if you feel it's great
to go through the intersessional group to
see how they could bring that in as well,
please.
Absolutely.
Especially when it comes to the of the
research side of stuff too.
The Denali, I think.
Yeah, There we go.
Permit.
I was like, I I knew somebody.
I was like, Danielle, I was like,
if you could post it.
So Danielle and then I like,
did you see what Danielle posted?
I meant.
And then Danielle's e-mail address.
And here's the link for the.
Yeah.
OK, So Danielle,
I should connect these faculty to you
directly.
That sounds great and exciting.
That's awesome.
That's perfect.
Yeah.
In addition,
on the second link that I sent all of our,
SO James,
Danielle and myself all have our contact
information pinned to the top of that
page.
Awesome.
That's great.
I appreciate you doing that too.
Because what we're about to get into is a
little bit more because there are people
that are on this call that weren't on
other calls from before.
And as we move into this last kind of
beat the intersectional work group ideas,
I want others that are interested in in
getting in touch with y'all to be part of
this intercession work to come back to
the next one to know who to contact.
So Gregory,
thanks for putting your contacts into
that.
So make sure and, and of course, as we go,
please put your e-mail address or contact
information in too, so we can gather more.
I really kind of do want to talk a little
bit about some of this interceptional
work group stuff because what I'm kind of
seeing is that and and I especially
appreciate Gregory and Danielle,
what you did today because it really
lines up perfectly with hopefully our
next road map to really get to this work
going.
And I feel that as we look at it,
our responsibilities for this group are
kind of three.
So as from our previous set of slides
there,
we have really reporting framework that
we need to come up with.
We have kind of harm reduction quality
improvement framework to come up with and
we have to come up with of course the
core and extended data set framework.
Those three things are our main core
responsibilities for this work group.
And while the other work groups are
working on things that are critical to
standing the program up to the the
propagation and the education training
committee.
So we have qualified, we have you know,
patient qualifications and patient safety,
things like that.
These three are kind of what we're
looking at,
but I hate this like we'll have these
broken down.
I really see that what y'all have come up
with in the intersection group work has
been there are three really three things
that it's sounding like,
because at the beginning I said, oh,
it's education for the community or it's
emerging preparedness or whatever it is.
But it really sounds like you have a a
care pathway and safety kind of group,
A participant experience and fit,
which really lines up with what Danielle
had just come up with.
And I, the third thing,
the data and reporting architecture,
both of y'all kind of came up with a lot
of that as like,
here's the stuff that needs to come back
in.
And I've got to give y'all a,
a big shout out because this helped
tremendously in your work to line out
kind of what the journey is for a,
a participant going from preparation into
the session into an integration phase and
then a follow up.
And then lastly,
kind of an oversight review,
which would be what will be bubbled up
from a lot of the data that gets in.
And again,
some of the work that y'all have done
kind of showed is that there are there
are there are tools that can be used
along the way and y'all have broken it
down into these Are you ready?
How are you doing?
What happened and is anything wrong
guidance.
So I think that that is a perfect kind of
framework to put this in and for the work
groups that y'all have is like what are
the kind of shared questions to have?
It's like what should happen at this
stage,
meaning for preparation or for session or
integration,
What risks or concerns are at this stage?
And you know, Danielle,
you broke that down actually in your
presentation to kind of show here are
some things that can be reported or
concerns along the way on what should be
documented,
then we need to think about then, OK,
because it's documented,
but what should be monitored or reviewed?
And then we also,
some of the first things we did in this
work group were to try to create kind of
a data structure, a data dictionary,
if you will.
But we started thinking about like, well,
what are the core and what are the
extended things?
Because there are certain things that we
need from every session,
every participant.
There are some things that might make
sense and more of a research idea that
might be in an extended data set too.
So that's kind of one of the things I
really wanted as we do our work to kind
of focus on.
So I felt that if we kind of like divided
up into that so that there is good like
right lines between the groups,
the care pathway and safety participant
experience and fit and data and reporting
that it would look like this is that we
could come up with kind of a,
a cadence for the work to do as that row.
The first one reporting framework we
would come up with first.
And then the second one would be the harm
reduction Paul improvement framework.
And the last one would be the the true
core and extended data set framework.
And I felt that like the work groups can
work together, all three, of course,
but they would,
there would be like a main 2 that would
be working for those things.
So, for example, the reporting,
the care and path,
the care pathway and safety,
which is regular with you and,
and James Brown and really have worked on.
And then of course,
data reporting and architecture.
I'm a little weak on that one.
I just don't think I have anybody at this
moment for that.
So I just wanted to kind of bring this up
as I kind of go through this list.
So Gregory, please go for it.
Just while it's on top of my head and I'm
saying this so that I remember it and
it's recorded, but in the data,
the data reporting and architecture,
one of the things that needs to be,
I think discovered or like, you know,
like a pathway for built is to trace long
term outcome data post de identification
through consent frameworks and like
whatever else.
I don't know,
like there is there is an there's a
traditional like de identification point
where like further data doesn't apply to
that individual.
And if we're going to try to track people
5 and 10 years later and see if they come
back and and stuff like that,
like how do we safely build that
architecture in that context?
I don't have an answer.
I would like to fix that.
Thank you very much.
Because that would be something that
would be squarely sat in the data
reporting architecture group,
because that's exactly right.
Because we've, we've not just, I mean,
you're, you're looking at a very Longview,
which is absolutely perfect.
But your core of that,
the de identification of data is
something that we talked about from the
very beginning.
We need to make sure that what we're
collecting is completely de identified,
but still trackable in some way.
So again, that's,
that's something that's that is something
that that data and reporting architecture
committee really or subcommittee needs to
really be focused on.
So exactly,
and I'm going to apologize upfront on
this.
So there's going to be this is going to
be very like wordy and heavy and and what
I'm about to share,
but it was the only way that I could
think about doing it so that I could get
it out to y'all and to see it.
So if you're looking at like, Oh my gosh,
this is unbelievable and and crazy, yes,
sorry,
but is the only way that I can kind of
think this through.
And again, we'll share the the the deck,
the slides and everything like so you can
see this offline.
But of course, if you're like, hey,
I want to take a snap of it so I can see
this offline, that's fine too.
So kind of to dig into those work groups,
this first one,
this care pathway and safety,
this is again where we, you know,
this is where the CATAE Pro,
those kind of things kind of fit in with
it.
It's the identifying, mapping the journey,
identifying where the risks,
the safeguards and response expectations
arise for if there's anybody on this,
this committee that's here that's like,
hey,
I really want to work on something like
this that you've already heard what
Gregory had kind of posted from the
intersection work.
This is somebody that's really strong in
harm reduction,
somebody that safety focused clinicians
would be great for this kind of group to
to be part of this and people familiar
with crisis response.
Evers,
I know that what we're just talking about
that Eileen had to jump off,
but Eileen comes to mind on this one as
well as well.
Main questions this group's going to have
to answer is what are the key risk points
along preparation section,
integration of follow up,
which I think y'all have already been
working on,
What safeguards should exist at each
stage, What events should be documented,
what requires escalation, of course,
going from challenging to adverse and
what patterns should trigger review or
change.
And so that kind of last bullet is
probably a longer conversation,
but it's something to be mindful of.
And so this is,
there's some specific deliverables I feel
that the group can kind of come up with
this care pathway map, a safeguard map,
event taxonomy,
those kind of things that makes sense in
that kind of like the the work that
you're talking about.
Gregory, this is where I try to break.
That's why I said it's going to be a
little worried.
But what I wanted to do is break down
each one of these kind of three groups as
to what they'll be doing and the
reporting framework,
the harm reduction quality improvement
framework and the core extended data set
framework.
So again, like I said,
those are our three kind of deliverables.
This group needs this our,
our ICI group needs to look at.
And so each one of these work groups kind
of defines a set from those 3.
And that's where I wanted to kind of show
is like, OK,
what can we do in this work group to,
to bring in certain things.
So I think that what you're already doing
is exactly in this direction.
And so for example, finding event tiers,
you know,
what if you whatever protocol that you
use, if it is the PATAE or the CATAE Pro,
looking at event tiers like this is just
a routine,
no incident all the way to serious
adverse event requiring external response
or formal review.
So that's,
I know what you're already working on.
So that's where your question asks to
what protocol do we want to to utilize.
I really feel this is where this work
group gets to say this is what we're
going to do.
So whatever that kind of comes out to,
I don't want to be the one that says
that's the one to use.
I feel that this work group needs to be
able to say that.
And I think y'all are well equipped to be
able to make that recommendation to our
whole work group for that to move forward.
And this would include any of those
screening tools,
anything that you've already been working
on and looking at in the research that
makes sense from this.
And then of course,
to kind of bubble up those things,
you know,
down towards the bottom of this column,
system integration or system learning
questions like are certain harms
happening repeatedly?
Emergency transfers clustered in certain
settings,
our consent and Prep reducing preventable
distress.
So those kind of things I feel can come
up with that kind of safety that are
already out there in the the clinical
practice groups or the patient safety
groups.
But really this kind of work group will
be talking a lot about how do we how do
we monitor that and report on that.
The second work group that participant
experience and fit and a lot of what
Danielle has been working on talks about
like what must be captured about
participant preferences, boundaries,
respect, cultural, spiritual fit,
affinity and participant reported harm or
mismatch.
So everything that you have talked about
today really fits into this.
The best people to work together on this
work group will be people who are strong
on patient clinician affinity,
focus on multicultural competence and
patient centered care,
and of course attempted to respect
boundaries and mismatch issues.
And so the main questions this group will
be talking about is what participant
preference should be asked about what
does a good fit look like?
And of course when we're talking about
this,
it's like we already have education and
training committee.
This is talking about what kind of data
can we look at here as to or are we
tracking good patient and clinician
affinity and fit?
So this is where just like Daniel talked
about, it's like there are tools that can,
can like,
is the participant feeling safe and heard
and respected?
Is there a cultural or spiritual mismatch,
those kind of things?
And how does it look from the provider or
the patient entering or providing this
information as a like a low, low traction?
So we don't want this to be something
that's onerous to either of them,
but something that it would look like.
And then this one kind of really fits in
a lot of the harm reduction and quality
improvement framework.
So this one's a little bit longer in this
work group of what they're going to be
looking at,
like our participants reporting that
their preferences were being ignored.
Are there patterns of anything which is
perfect?
It's kind of what Gregory brought up
about.
Somebody's bias might change the outcomes
of their sessions.
And so there's some quality improvement
sections like what do we do?
Can we help provide recommendations for
the consent content or facilitator
training or anything like that?
The and then of course patterns that
could trigger like referrals over to our
equity access and cultural considerations
committee.
So those are some things from that.
This goes into now second set,
which is the data.
So the data that this work group might
recommend is like what can we collect in
a data system?
And of course it has to be something that
could be collected in a data system.
So I want to kind of make that note there
is that this is the work that we'll have
to work together from this work group and
the last work group,
the data and reporting architecture.
And this work group at this moment,
I feel for, for, for me is like,
this is the the part that I just don't
have a lot of a lot of other people
working on right now.
So I'm going to say for me as like this
is one that I will ask for some help on.
So if there's anybody out there that
feels like, hey,
I'm really good and strong on the data
reporting and architecture concept,
this would really be very helpful to at
the end of this to kind of say, yeah,
I could help with this because these are
people that are good with databases who
are systems, thinkers, operations,
can distinguish between what's ideal and
what is feasible.
So what Gregory just mentioned about like
this long term de identify thing,
this is exactly what these individuals
will be helpful for.
And that's this group's going to talk
about what is the core data that we need
to collect versus what's the kind of
extent that would be great on research.
There's going to be a lot of things that
come in qualitatively.
Instead of quantitatively.
So how can we capture some of that in a
data system and then report out on that
as well?
And what should be structured for
reporting and oversight and what should
be aggregated for review?
So these would be things like that data
dictionary and and those kind of things
that come from it.
So there are some work that gets done
together for reporting framework and harm
reduction of course.
And some of them the for example drop out
rate was on here.
I remember we added that into our data
dictionary.
But what are some of the patterns we're
seeing?
Are we seeing mismatch trends,
disparities against certain groups or
ethnicities or race?
And is there site to site variation?
And this one's the big one because
there's so much data that has to be kind
of collected in this.
And so that group is really responsible
for that.
So I just, you know,
really want to to just throw this out
here is that there's a lot I know of work
to be added into this.
But I want to go back to this and ask
everybody.
It's like,
do you feel that this kind of structure
that I've put together here is helpful
for the next set of directions for this
group?
And like I said,
I apologize for giving so much, you know,
words out here,
but and I'll drop it into chat and of
course we'll post it.
But I just wanted to ask,
is this helpful moving forward again to
show that these are the three kind of
committees that that the work groups for
intersessional work.
And so you can raise your hands and throw
slings and arrows at me to say, wow,
that was super complicated.
But I just felt it made a lot of sense to
to say,
here's instead of calling it adverse and
challenging events,
intersessional group and patient.
So this kind of helps to say,
where can we fit in this?
So I just wanted to ask that and I'll
drop in to the chat.
Also a link where you can find this
information too.
So everything that I've kind of shared
with you today,
I hope that you will be able to see it
even offline.
There it goes.
So please feel free to open your mic,
raise your hands,
let me know what you think.
And especially if there is something that
you wanted to say like, hey,
I want to be working with that group
because again,
you've got some awesome people You've got
already Gregory Evans, who's, you know,
been really on the Karen pathway and
safety.
And then of course,
Danielle has been focused on the petition
participant experience and fit,
But like I said,
I don't really have anything for data and
reporting architecture.
So, oh, Danielle Leonard.
Yes, I would like to join group three,
Group 3,
the data recording and architecture group
Danielle.
Yes, that's sort of my area.
I just sort of segwayed off into
multicultural when asked, but but yeah, I,
I do do research and do work with
statistics.
So I love that.
Well,
I don't want you because one of the
things that we had talked about was that
it's very difficult to have like doing
all the same thing, you know.
So I want to make sure, you know,
Eileen Brewer seems to be very, you know,
see, I, I'm voluntary.
She's not even here,
but something on the participant
experience of fit.
And you've already done, you know, the,
the yeoman's effort to get that started.
So do you feel that you want to like or
do you want to, I mean,
you'll be working across both of course,
but do you feel you want to be like a
strong lead for data boarding
architecture?
And if you say yes, that's fantastic.
For me, I,
I'm just really interested in how we're
going to do the battery.
I'm really aware of participant burden.
I think that we probably need to try to
come up with something for 30 minutes.
We could do, you know,
we could do work with branching and skip
logic and branching logic and stuff to
try to get there.
And I'm also just aware of the,
the measures and the,
the validities and alphas and sort of
into that.
Yep.
But I'm happy to jump in on the,
the fit as well because I am a therapist
and I care deeply about that.
Well, as you can see, it's like, you know,
at the bottom of this slide is that
that's exactly there's a lot of overlap
an affinity to work.
It's just there are the like this time,
this kind of group stands out and to do
some of that work and there is the cross
work there.
So appreciate that.
And I just want to hit something in the
Catherine Warnock.
Thank you.
I can help with groups one and two.
Absolutely.
Thank you very much because that's going
to be super helpful on that.
Ian said, hey, I've got head out.
Appreciate the work everybody's doing
here.
And then I saw Gregory had his hands up,
and now it's gone.
Well, let's see.
It looks like we've also got Lisa
Ginsburg with her hand up and.
Oh, sorry about that.
I did not.
Yeah, did not see Lisa down on there.
Open.
I had my menu over it.
No worries.
All right, Lisa, your mic is enabled.
You can unmute when ready.
Thank you.
Thank you for this information.
Was really helpful I'm happy to offer
support for all the groups through our
team would love to hear how often these
groups how often they meet and how much
time and commitment would you require for
this so I'm gonna throw this one up here
real quick because this is kind of our
cadence that I've already kind of blocked
for us to have the courthouse.
So for our next this group's next meeting
would be June 12th,
followed by July 10th and August 7th.
And so the intercessional work happens
between that time.
And I'm going to let kind of like I think
that Gregory might have his hand up on
that one to probably answer that as well
because he'd probably give a little bit
more, you know,
conversation about how much work is to be
expected kind of offline, how often,
Because I do know that y'all probably
have visits as well.
So Oh yeah.
I mean,
I don't think it's really established.
I think James,
Danielle and I kind of targeted meeting
as we could.
We maybe meet once or twice between
meetings and I think we do independent
work between that and some of the like
how much effort is it comes with like
your background and your expertise
because like you may have actually worked
for 20 years to gain the knowledge that
you bring to a one hour meeting.
So as far as like our experience,
it's been a fair bit of work.
I kind of like collect a lot of the data
and present it and like create the hub of
information.
Like I'm a glorified secretary,
I think in that respect.
But I did wanna say I was hoping more
data nerds would raise their hands.
But you know,
like that is my like core functionality
in this in this world is data
architecture and program management.
So I'm not gonna let you be alone on that,
Danielle.
I'm looking forward to getting into that.
I also was curious if,
and I know I've asked this,
I'll continue to ask if the department
has any forward movement on the
conversation of what that looks like,
their needs,
what their needs are for that engine,
if that question makes sense.
Yeah,
I think that that will be a beneficial
question because if there's anything from
from maybe Dominic,
if I'm going to put you on the spot,
if you're out there,
if there is anything the Department of
Health wants to kind of talk about,
about any kind of data governance
structure, database,
I mean whatever you want to talk about,
because that is going to be our next kind
of thing to jump into.
Don't say do it right.
And thank you, Dan and and Greg as well.
And, and the answer to that is no,
that's actually a part of what all of
this is really about is to help determine
what type of data is necessary and what
really is going to help balance between,
you know, for the,
the difference with ensuring patients are
getting served and not experiencing
survey fatigue or data collection fatigue,
for example.
And what actually would fall in under
research categories.
So once there is funding for various
research projects,
what types of projects should be,
you know, what, what should,
what data should those projects be
focused on?
And that's actually a part of what we're
relying on this committee and
subcommittee to really determine.
And we don't want to try to direct it and
say this is exactly what should happen
because anytime that that that occurs,
we end up missing things.
And we don't want to do that.
We would like to have that broad base to
start and then start narrowing things
down based upon the other aspects,
whether it be funding, budgets, timelines,
things like that.
But right now they're, you know,
it's really broad and open at this point
in time.
Thanks for that.
Yeah.
Does that, I mean,
I don't know if that kind of gets to the
crux what you're looking for,
but I think that could be the
recommendation that we could put out
there too.
No, I think that's great.
That's a good place to start.
Open field.
Yeah.
So think of it as something where y'all
can from from y'all's intercessional
group to be able to say here's kind of
what we make that recommendation that we
utilize.
Let's let's let's go down that route.
All right.
And Brenda, yes, I thank you.
Well,
this was a lot of meat and potatoes here.
I really love seeing all of this because
I I love data too.
I really love all of that.
But as a clinician and actually part of
like cheering the education and training,
I would like to see like a mock up of
just what we need to collect as
therapists in for our our clients.
And,
and it's like what Dominic was saying,
we don't want to be of, you know,
fatigued from collecting all of this
information, But jeez,
all this information is vital.
You know, it's like, oh, we all,
we all need this because this is how
we're we're gonna be able to move forward.
But maybe having something that's
manageable and concise with collecting
this data and also like feeding that data
into a program where you're going to be
getting the, you know,
the stats correct that you need in order
to provide, you know,
future research on this.
You know, and I'm,
I'm going to jump in on that too.
You're exactly right.
The whole idea for this is not to say
collecting data for data's sake.
The idea is honestly continuous
improvement and not from,
not on our side because I don't want it
to be something where practitioners are
utilizing a data system in which they
only,
they only hear about it whenever bad
things take place.
The whole concept of this is how can we
implement this on a quick turn around so
that even the practitioners in the field
are getting good actionable data about
their practice, their patients.
And that's the true continuous
improvement.
So again,
I I would love this to be like if you're
putting as a clinician information into a
system that it is coming back to you
quickly for continuous improvements in
your own practice.
That's my feel longer.
Yeah.
And the programming this is, is very well,
I've worked with a lot of programmers and
what what happens a lot of times they get
into their heads and they're going, oh,
this would be really great to put this in.
And then it,
it doesn't really relate or it doesn't
really, it's not vital information.
So it, you know,
having somebody that really knows what
kind of material that we need to collect
is really vital with all of that.
Absolutely.
Thank you.
That's very true.
And also I'm going to,
I should say I want this to be actionable
for the participant as well so that the
participant knows that they're actually
on on this journey too.
So,
so I'm going to jump over real quick into
Lisa Ginsburg.
What's the best way to connect if we want
to offer support?
And Gregor Evans said the above link
summarizes the time impact across pathway
collections and plain language,
which is extrapolated from Danielle's
input from 410 the racy meeting,
which is true.
It was like,
I know that that work group really worked
on trying to say that here's here's what
it looks like and time wise,
not a long time, but short amount of time.
So there's a little bit of that mock up
you asked about in the at above length
that great reposted and Eileen says I'd
like to help out with Group 1.
Thank you, Eileen.
So Gregory, go ahead.
You always do that when I'm typing on the
other screen.
I know I used to work food service,
so I'd come around whenever somebody had,
you know, like taking that bite.
So that's that's what I do.
I think the first thing is I'm pretty
sure I lost my train of thought I got.
I'm just reacting.
It's OK.
I think you were typing and probably to
respond back what Brenda was talking
about because I saw your hand go up right
at that same time and then you did type
in that.
There is some information there for for
Lisa's question, make sure that Lisa,
if you do want office support,
just kind of say your e-mail address and
probably the chat and what group that
you're interested in,
whether it be the safety or the patient
chat or the data,
kind of like what I did too.
Yeah, to Brenda's question,
a lot of that is outlined in the link
that I posted.
Danielle did an extremely detailed
assessment of time cost on what
instruments and then we separated out
into pathway impact.
So if person is going through one of the
four pathways of treatment of qualifying
conditions,
there are certain things that are
universal that that should be tracked and
certain things that like are more pathway
specific.
And then there's other events that
trigger certain types of data collection
or additional instruments to be accrued.
I'm looking for another link and I'll
post it just below this that has more of
that breakdown in detail,
which I think might help understand.
But really, I mean,
it's like over the course of four months,
we're looking at a couple of hours and
it's the clinician's job to collect data
and the clinicians are tends to be,
you know, used to that sort of thing.
And without like revealing too much,
I think that there will be potential for
tools being developed that will minimize
the impact and streamline the data,
data collection on instruments through,
you know,
a handful of to be defined tools.
I have a plan.
Thank you very much.
And because I know that on there was a
document that was shared for contact
information, but feel free to drop your,
like I said,
e-mail into the chat and I'm sure they'll
capture it to reach out to you.
And Eileen,
I don't think that they've got your
contact information as well.
So you can be on that,
that kind of intersessional work as well.
So like I said,
appreciate the help on all of this.
Number one,
because this has been so instrumental in
kind of moving us forward.
The idea like I said for our next,
our next meeting will be June 12th.
And at that time I would love for the
intersessional groups to be able to kind
of put out that reporting framework
consensus, whatever that might look like.
And remember on that is that I've dropped
it in that link into the chat what that
what might look like kind of go back
through my slides to get to that.
So when we talk about reporting framework,
these were some of the things here.
I don't think you could see my pointer.
So this is kind of the reporting
framework from from the care pathway and
safety group.
And this is the kind of reporting
framework that comes out from participant
experience and fit and then from the data
reporting.
This is the kind of reporting framework.
So this it would be a great thing to to
be able to kind of combine all of y'all's
work and present that on the June 12th,
because then that sets that framework
that everything else can kind of fall
into place from that.
Again,
all three intercessional groups kind of
work together on their own thing during
that time,
but they're reporting back for this first
part for the June 12th.
And then after that the June like 10th
would be then bringing up here's the harm
reduction and quality improvement
framework and bringing that consensus to
work.
And then the last one, of course,
the 7th of August would be the court
extended data set.
So that's really where we can make that
big recommendation as to here's what that
data set might look like.
And then I've also reserved the September
11th meeting there and it just says to be
determined.
So I just wanted to be that as like
whatever might need to be kind of
hangover at work that way we can be at
that.
So that way for our next meeting,
June 12th,
we won't be talking about a whole lot of
stuff.
We'll be just talking about this one
thing, reporting framework, consensus.
So everybody that's on that call will
hear from the interceptional work groups
reporting out what they feel the
reporting framework would look like.
And we would then come to a consensus at
that time to say that sounds great,
let's solidify that and we'll move on.
So that way the groups can work on the
next thing,
harm reduction call improvement framework.
Again,
we'll make consensus at that meeting and
then that way we'll move on to the data
set.
And then once we do that,
we can kind of set that in place.
So that's where I just wanted to say it's
like, please.
You know,
make sure that if you're interested in
that you're kind of looped in and
connected, you can always reach out.
And of course, Jonathan put in the chat.
You can find the sign up for committee
meetings here and there's a link for that
Gregory Ives post at the time burden
estimates.
So that's kind of where I want to kind of
get our, like I said,
our cadence moving forward so that we'll
now start to build out our kind of voting
and making the recommendations out to the
the board as a whole as we go through
this.
And I think that that way if we're ready
by the September 11th,
then we'll actually have some data
components ready because if January 1
comes around,
we'll have to have a data system set up
and established along with the patient's
harm reduction,
quality improvement and reporting for
adverse and challenging experiences and
such.
So that gives us,
I think a really good thing that we can
work on independent,
but in conjunction with some of those
other work groups.
So would love to hear I mean,
if if you feel that that's doable,
if you feel that's insane,
but I would just love to hear some of
that on there.
Also for the Group 3,
these are some of the things that we had
oops had talked about before.
I'm just jump back to some of these quick
slides here, the data collection system.
These are some of the things that we have
worked on as a draft from some of our
previous meetings.
So that was also in the link that I threw
in there.
So these were some of the things we
talked about and feel free to utilize
them or to take them in in a different
direction as you all go to SO.
And so at this time,
just want to make sure that you have all
the information already put into the chat.
Of course,
how to send public comments here.
So you've got that information in the
chat as well.
I also want to leave this last bit of
time for y'all to have any kind of public
comments.
So this is now I will stop talking since
I've shared most of that stuff myself.
And so I want you all to be able to open
your mics up and kind of share anything
that you would like about the work.
Anything, our next steps,
things that we need to look at, feel free.
So please raise your hand.
We'll unmute your mic and we've got about
15 minutes left of the session,
so you've got plenty of time.
All right, let's see.
Jay Webster.
Sorry, I, I forgot your first name,
but your, your mic is enabled.
You can unmute.
Thank you.
Can I ask Gregory Evans to please repeat?
I, I wasn't familiar with the acronyms.
I I believe they're reporting framework
models that are being decided upon.
I think it's very important that we can
differentiate between a concerning event
versus an adverse event.
Which one of the frameworks would allow
us to make that distinction?
Yeah, that's great question.
It's a lot of letters that all sound the
same.
So the CATAE,
the AE part stands for adverse events.
So cancer something, something.
Dan Danielle, I can't recall,
but basically the CATAE is a reporting,
an oncological reporting structure for
adverse events in treatment of cancer.
It is kind of a broad standard across
multiple industries because no one has
built an instrument as effective as that.
They made a Pro version.
I don't know what Pro stands for,
but essentially the PRO Dash version of
that is an instrument that can be adapted
by any program without going through the
process of developing a new framework,
becoming an instrument,
codifying that into the lexicon of
whatever says that an instrument is an
instrument.
Now there is a researcher out of Emory
University named Doctor Politsky who
developed a framework, not an instrument,
a framework called PATAE,
which is psychedelic assisted therapy,
adverse event tracking.
One of those links,
one of those first links that I posted
all the knowing flight is just what my
notes trap my notes program publishes as.
So in there there's detailed information
about how the PATAE can apply to our
needs and the yeah,
that I was just going to say, Danielle,
common terminology criteria for adverse
expense it's events.
And to to that question that you had as
well is that, as you said,
it's like the difference between what's
an adverse event reportable?
What's the difference between the
challenging of that?
It really comes down to exactly what the,
the patient's,
the the the safety kind of work group
gets to talk about is like these are
things that are reportable events that
would be on that protocol.
And here are things that are just
challenging events that are duly noted
and part of session, but not as part of,
for lack of a better term,
a red flag that might come up.
So that would do something like that.
So again,
that's part of this intersessional work
group to say that off of whatever
protocol is chosen,
here's those items that are definitely
reportable and, and, and actionable.
Yeah.
And, and, and to to cap that the the so,
so it is a framework that Politsky at all
has developed.
It is in version 0.1.
So they're like they, they,
they're publicly saying this exists,
it's out there.
We don't have a final product.
And our goal is to connect with their
team to see how we can either a fast
track that if they already have the,
the pathway towards becoming an
instrument in place,
that can take like one to five years.
We don't have the time needed to develop
an instrument,
but we want to be able to utilize and
leverage the information in that
framework by modifying the pro CATAE as a
stopgap to allow us to to be able to
understand the and define the difference
between challenging and adverse events.
If it does that answer all your your
question.
Very thorough answer.
Thank you.
Cool.
I've read way too much about that.
There's a Canadian study on end of life
care, palliative care,
that is utilizing this framework and it
is in process and I'll find a link and
put it in there.
It's an incredible study.
I love the Canadians, but yeah,
it's a wonderful application of this
framework.
All right.
And I see I mute this hand up and you can
unmute when you're ready.
Oops.
Hi.
Can you hear me?
Yep.
Yay.
OK.
Good morning, everybody.
Wonderful meeting.
I'm so happy to be able to attend today.
And thank you Gregory for making the
announcement at the last in the live
committee meeting about this,
about this meeting and the contents of
this sort of cross pollination,
which is super important.
So I am the Co director of the
Psychedelic Mental Health Access Alliance.
We're a national organization and we're
doing some of our first pilot studies and
work here in New Mexico,
which is super exciting.
Partnering doctor Larry Lehman for the
group psilocybin assisted therapy for
PTSD study.
And as a part of that,
it is something that Gregory also touched
on,
we are piloting a tool that we're calling
the Circle of Care.
And it's just something I would love for
this committee and really all of the
committees in the state to think about
that continuum of care that might be
happening outside of the clinical
protocol,
but that is absolutely essential and
important toward actually harm reduction.
So when you have ongoing integration
support,
you're gonna see less a less likeliness
right of harm happening of people moving
into, you know, difficult spaces alone.
And so offering up,
I would love to to know, you know,
when you're guys are talking about these
adverse events and tracking these things,
like what is the time frame by which
you're Speaking of?
Is it within a certain amount of time
after the last integration?
That's a part of the clinical model.
Does it extend past that?
And would love to think about how can
this committee help PMHA come up with
some of the data points that we should be
tracking in terms of the effectiveness of
an ongoing integration support model?
Thank you.
If I can respond to that,
I think you might have a little bit more
insight into this than most people,
but I don't think a lot of frameworks and
studies are tracking adverse events after
the outside of the dosage experience.
And it really is groundbreaking to just
think of the idea of holistic lifelong
care.
And so I'm all for it.
And I, I think you're well aware that I'm,
I'm here for the idea room.
If yeah,
I'm not going to ask you to commit more
of your time than to, to this world of,
of developing tools than than you're
already committed to.
But your insight is, is welcome here.
Yeah.
That's a wonderful thing that I say about
this group is that if you come into it
and you say, hey,
I've got something and then you're part
of it.
So.
Because your expertise,
that's the whole point of this group is
the expertise of everybody.
Everybody has something to share.
This is I,
I keep saying is I'm a conductor.
Y'all are the actual orchestra that are
the ones that are super trained and super
experienced.
So I'm,
I'm just happy to be part of the group.
So if you can share, please,
please do and be part of it.
So I don't think that anybody right now
is saying here's exactly the way that
we're going to do it.
Everything is kind of ability to be
flexible.
So please know that you know that you're
welcome at this table.
Thank you so much.
And Brenda, I don't, yeah, I just wanted,
I just wanted to kind of look at that for
just a moment and the the long term data
collection on that.
And, you know, all of this is great,
but all of this costs money too.
So.
But if we could, you know,
have something like that as kind of
placeholder to look at as far as because,
yeah,
no one's really looked at the long term
effects.
And it's like,
I think like I'm going back to a study
that Magic Johnson did with smoking
cessation and I think they did a follow
up I think after two years, you know,
and that was still robust.
I mean,
people were still not smoking after
psilocybin treatment.
So yeah,
we're all we're looking at like funding
for long term, you know,
either adverse effects or positive
effects and,
and seeing what that looks like because.
I think any one of us who have had
experiences with psilocybin or or good or
adverse experiences, yeah,
we still continue to feel that long,
long after it's been administered and you
know, you've had that experience.
So I just wanted to throw my two cents in
about that.
No perfect, Brandon, thank you very much.
And in the chat K talk,
it said in my experience,
most serious adverse events show up in
the days and weeks after the psychedelic
session that we're looking at this.
So yeah, you've definitely,
it's perfect thing to bring up.
So thank you.
We've got 5 more minutes left.
Is there any other comments that anybody
would like to make?
Can you hear me?
I just want to jump in and say that's the
sort of care pilot,
it will be a part of this group
psilocybin assisted therapy pilot.
So we'll going to run it 3 for three
months after each cohort finishes their
fifteen week protocol.
So we will be collecting,
you know both qualitative and
quantitative data on its impact.
An important thing to also lift is that
the services and resources will not only
be available to the participants,
but also to their families and loved ones
to provide them with support and skills
and training to support their their
family member that's just come through
this this treatment.
Thank you.
Thank you for hearing that Anita and then
Gregory Evans in the chat.
Yes to positive effects.
One of my primary interests is continued
research on the window of plasticity and
the frameworks that allow care teams to
support that over time.
Well,
I cannot thank everybody so much for a
wonderful meeting.
Like I said,
I really appreciate us to be able to kind
of come together on that level setting
for where we sit in our committee and
where we can help out in the roles of
other committees and where our role and
fit really are and the work that's going
to happen now for this next set of
sprints that we're going to be doing for
the next one coming up on June 12th.
I really hope that y'all are able to make
it to our June 12th meeting so that you
can hear from the interceptional group
reporting out on what their reporting
framework will look like.
And I cannot, like I said,
thank y'all enough for being here and
spending your time not just at this
meeting,
at the other committee meetings and also
as part of this intersectional work
because I know that it's a lot of time
for everybody.
But cannot thank you enough for sharing
your expertise to building an amazing
safe New Mexico medical psilocybin
program.
Don't forget that there are additional
work groups that are going on.
Brenda's is coming up later this
afternoon for education and training.
So please make sure you register for that
and that way you can come to the next
group to later today.
So otherwise,
thank you all very much for your day.
Have a great weekend.
I really appreciate it and hope you get
to have a wonderful one.
Take care.
And I I also just want to say the
Brenda's meeting will also include the
end of life care committee.
So those two meetings are together today.
Yeah, combined.
Thank you.
Perfect.
Thank you, Dan.
Perfect.
Thank you very much, Gregory, Danielle,
everybody that participated and shared
and I really like I said, it's fantastic,
Eileen, for your help everybody out there.
So thank you all and thank you, Dan,
and thank you everybody.
I hope you all have a great and safe
Friday and weekend.
Happy Mother's Day as well.
Yes, absolutely.
Thank you, DoH team.
Thank you all.
Have a great rest of your day.